export const questions = [
  
    {
      "question": "What does HTML stand for?",
      "options": ["Hypertext Markup Language", "Hyperlink Text Markup Language", "High Text Markup Language", "Hypertext Mailing Language"],
      "answer": "Hypertext Markup Language",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "question": "In a loop, what statement is used to repeat a block of code?",
      "options": ["if", "switch", "for", "while"],
      "answer": "for",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the correct syntax to declare a variable in JavaScript?",
      "options": ["var name = value", "let name = value", "const name = value", "All of the above"],
      "answer": "All of the above",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of a function in programming?",
      "options": ["To group a reusable block of code", "To define a variable", "To create a loop", "To define a conditional statement"],
      "answer": "To group a reusable block ofcode",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does CSS stand for?",
      "options": ["Cascading Style Sheets", "Coded Style Script", "Colorful Style Script", "Creative Style Sheet"],
      "answer": "Cascading Style Sheets",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of an API?",
      "options": ["To define the structure of a database", "To create a user interface", "To store and manage data","To define how applications interact with each other"],
      "answer": "To define how applications interact with each other",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does DOM stand for?",
      "options": ["Style Definition", "Document Structure", "User Interaction"],
      "answer": "Document Structure",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a common version control system used by programmers?",
      "options": ["Git", "SVN", "CVS", "All of the above"],
      "answer": "All of the above",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of debugging in programming?",
      "options": ["To optimize code performance","To find and fix errors in code", "To write new code features", "To test code functionality"],
      "answer": "To find and fix errors in code",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does IDE stand for?",
      "options": ["Independent Development Environment", "Interactive Development Environment","Integrated Development Environment", "Internal Development Environment"],
      "answer": "Integrated Development Environment",
      "category": "coding"
    },
  
  // Sports
  {
    question: "Which sport features a birdie as a desirable outcome?",
    options: ["Basketball", "Cricket", "Badminton", "Soccer"],
    answer: "Badminton",
    category: "sports",
  },
  {
    question: "Which sport uses the most water in a professional competition?",
    options: ["Rowing", "Tennis", "Gymnastics", "Baseball"],
    answer: "Rowing",
    category: "sports",
  },
  {
    question: "In which sport is a “triple-double” a noteworthy achievement?",
    options: ["Volleyball", "Hockey", "Basketball", "American Football"],
    answer: "Basketball",
    category: "sports",
  },

  {
    question: "Which sport awards points for a “knockout”?",
    options: ["Boxing", "Figure Skating", "Archery", "Golf"],
    answer: "Boxing",
    category: "sports",
  },
  {
    question: "Which sport uses a “shinguard” as protective equipment?",
    options: ["Swimming", "Soccer", "Cycling", "Table Tennis"],
    answer: "Soccer",
    category: "sports",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In which sport is a “hypsometer” used to measure the distance of a throw?",
    options: ["Weightlifting", "Discus Throw", "Marathon", "Javelin Throw"],
    answer: "Discus Throw",
    category: "sports",
  },
  {
    question: "Which sport requires competitors to wear a “whitesuit”?",
    options: ["Formula One Racing", "Cricket", "Tennis", "Basketball"],
    answer: "Cricket",
    category: "sports",
  },
  {
    question: "Which sport uses a “pommel horse” as an apparatus?",
    options: ["Gymnastics", "Figure Skating", "Horse Racing", "Archery"],
    answer: "Gymnastics",
    category: "sports",
  },
  {
    question: "In which sport is a “birdie” a penalty?",
    options: ["Curling", "Golf", "Bowling", "Snooker"],
    answer: "Golf",
    category: "sports",
  },
  {
    question: "Which sport uses a “wicket” as part of the playing field?",
    options: ["Baseball", "Cricket", "Rugby", "Tennis"],
    answer: "Cricket",
    category: "sports",
  },
  // movies
  {
    question:
      'Which movie is known for the iconic line "May the Force be with you"?',
    options: [
      "Star Trek: The Wrath of Khan",
      "Alien",
      "2001: A Space Odyssey",
      "Star Wars Episode IV: A New Hope",
    ],
    answer: "Star Wars Episode IV: A New Hope",
    category: "movies",
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the name of the spaceship in the movie "Alien"?',
    options: ["Millennium Falcon","Nostromo", "Enterprise", "Serenity"],
    answer: "Nostromo",
    category: "movies",
  },
  {
    question: 'Who directed the classic crime film "The Godfather"?',
    options: [
      "Martin Scorsese",
      "Francis Ford Coppola",
      "Quentin Tarantino",
      "Steven Spielberg",
    ],
    answer: "Francis Ford Coppola",
    category: "movies",
  },
  {
    question: 'What animated movie features the song "Hakuna Matata"?',
    options: ["Bambi", "Pocahontas", "Moana","The Lion King",],
    answer: "The Lion King",
    category: "movies",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which trilogy is known for its portrayal of hobbits, wizards, and orcs?",
    options: [
      "The Lord of the Rings",
      "The Chronicles of Narnia",
      "Harry Potter",
      "Pirates of the Caribbean",
    ],
    answer: "The Lord of the Rings",
    category: "movies",
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the name of the fictional world depicted in the "Avatar" movies?',
    options: ["Wakanda", "Middle-earth","Pandora", "Hogwarts"],
    answer: "Pandora",
    category: "movies",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which psychological thriller movie features a young boy who can see dead people?",
    options: ["The Shining", "Inception", "Black Swan","The Sixth Sense"],
    answer: "The Sixth Sense",
    category: "movies",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the superhero whose alter ego is Bruce Wayne?",
    options: ["Batman", "Superman", "Iron Man", "Captain America"],
    answer: "Batman",
    category: "movies",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which classic romantic comedy features Julia Roberts and Richard Gere?",
    options: [
      "When Harry Met Sally",
      "Sleepless in Seattle",
      "Pretty Woman",
      "You've Got Mail",
    ],
    answer: "Pretty Woman",
    category: "movies",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who directed the critically acclaimed science fiction film "Interstellar"?',
    options: [
      "Denis Villeneuve",
      "Ridley Scott",
      "James Cameron",
      "Christopher Nolan",
    ],
    answer: "Christopher Nolan",
    category: "movies",
  },
  // Science
  {
    question: "What is the smallest unit of matter?",
    options: [
      "Molecule", 
      "Cell", 
      "Atom", 
    "Organism"],
    answer: "Atom",
    category: "science",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The theory of evolution by natural selection is credited to which scientist?",
    options: [
      "Isaac Newton",
      "Charles Darwin",
      "Albert Einstein",
      "Stephen Hawking",
    ],
    answer: "Charles Darwin",
    category: "science",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the process by which plants convert sunlight into energy?",
    options: ["Photosynthesis", "Cellular respiration", "Mitosis", "Meiosis"],
    answer: "Photosynthesis",
    category: "science",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the study of the Earth and its atmosphere called?",
    options: ["Astronomy", "Biology","Geology", "Chemistry"],
    answer: "Geology",
    category: "science",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which element on the periodic table makes up the majority of the Earth's core?",
    options: ["Oxygen", "Hydrogen", "Helium","Iron"],
    answer: "Iron",
    category: "science",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the process by which water changes its state from a liquid to a gas?",
    options: ["Condensation","Evaporation", "Precipitation", "Sublimation"],
    answer: "Evaporation",
    category: "science",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the basic unit of heredity containing genetic information?",
    options: ["Chromosome", "Cell", "Gene", "Tissue"],
    answer: "Gene",
    category: "science",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The study of the structure and function of the human body is called?",
    options: ["Physiology","Gene", "Zoology", "Botany"],
    answer: "Anatomy",
    category: "science",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the theory that explains the origin and evolution of the universe?",
    options: [
      "String Theory",
      "Quantum Mechanics",
      "General Relativity",
      "The Big Bang Theory",
    ],
    answer: "The Big Bang Theory",
    category: "science",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the force that attracts objects with mass towards each other?",
    options: [
      "Electromagnetism",
      "The Strong Nuclear Force",
      "Gravity",
      "The Weak Nuclear Force",
    ],
    answer: "Gravity",
    category: "science",
  },
  // History

  {
    question: "What historical event marked the end of World War I?",
    options: [
      "The dropping of the atomic bomb on Hiroshima",
      "The storming of the Bastille",
      "The assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand",
      "The signing of the Treaty of Versailles"
    ],
    answer: "The signing of the Treaty of Versailles",
    category: "history",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which ancient civilization is known for its pyramids and hieroglyphics?",
    options: [
      "Mesopotamia",
      "Ancient Greece",
      "Ancient Egypt",
      "The Indus Valley Civilization",
    ],
    answer: "Ancient Egypt",
    category: "history",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Renaissance was a period of cultural and intellectual rebirth that began in which region?",
    options: [
      "Italian Peninsula",
      "Ancient China",
      "The Byzantine Empire",
      "The Aztec Empire",
    ],
    answer: "Italian Peninsula",
    category: "history",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who led the American colonists to victory in the Revolutionary War?",
    options: [
      "Benjamin Franklin",
      "Thomas Jefferson",
      "George Washington",
      "John Adams",
    ],
    answer: "George Washington",
    category: "history",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The fall of which city is considered the symbolic end of the Roman Empire?",
    option: ["Constantinople", "Rome", "Carthage", "Jerusalem"],
    answer: "Constantinople",
    category: "history",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Industrial Revolution was a period of rapid technological advancement that began in which country?",
    options: ["France","Great Britain", "Germany", "The United States"],
    answer: "Great Britain",
    category: "history",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The storming of the Bastille prison is a significant event in the history of which revolution?",
    options: [
      "American Revolution",
      "Russian Revolution",
      "Haitian Revolution",
      "French Revolution",
    ],
    answer: "French Revolution",
    category: "history",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The policy of appeasement was a failed attempt to prevent World War II by making concessions to which Nazi leader?",
    options: [
      "Joseph Stalin",
      "Adolf Hitler",
      "Benito Mussolini",
      "Hirohito",
    ],
    answer: "Adolf Hitler",
    category: "history",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Civil Rights Movement was a struggle for racial equality in which country?",
    options: ["United States", "South Africa", "Brazil", "Australia"],
    answer: "United States",
    category: "history",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Cold War was a period of geopolitical tension between which two superpowers?",
    options: [
      "Great Britain and France",
      "The United States and China",
      "The Soviet Union and Germany",
      "The United States and the Soviet Union",
    ],
    answer: "The United States and the Soviet Union",
    category: "history",
  },
  // Music
  {
    question:
      "Which genre of music is characterized by its use of strong rhythms and bluesy elements?",
    options: ["Blues", "Country", "Classical", "Hip Hop"],
    answer: "Blues",
    category: "music",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the four-member British rock band formed in Liverpool in 1960?",
    options: ["The Rolling Stones", "Queen","The Beatles", "Pink Floyd"],
    answer: "The Beatles",
    category: "music",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What instrument is known for its distinctive, mellow sound and ability to bend notes?",
    options: ["Trumpet", "Clarinet", "Flute", "Saxophone"],
    answer: "Saxophone",
    category: "music",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which musical period is known for its complex compositions and use of counterpoint?",
    options: [ "Renaissance", "Classical","Baroque", "Romantic"],
    answer: "Baroque",
    category: "music",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the term used to describe a singer who performs solo with a band or orchestra?",
    options: ["Instrumentalist", "Composer", "Conductor","Vocalist",],
    answer: "Vocalist",
    category: "music",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the annual music awards ceremony recognizing achievements in the American music industry?",
    options: [
      "American Music Awards",
      "MTV Video Music Awards",
      "Billboard Music Awards",
      "Grammy Awards",
    ],
    answer: "Grammy Awards",
    category: "music",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the term used to describe a musical piece with three distinct movements?",
    options: ["Concerto", "Symphony", "Sonata", "Quartet"],
    answer: "Symphony",
    category: "music",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the genre of music that originated in African-American communities in the early 20th century?",
    options: ["Blues","Jazz", "Rock and Roll", "Gospel"],
    answer: "Jazz",
    category: "music",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the term used to describe a group of singers performing together?",
    options: ["Band", "Orchestra","Choir", "Ensemble"],
    answer: "Choir",
    category: "music",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the musical notation system used to represent musical pitches and rhythms?",
    options: ["Sheet music", "Tablature", "Solfege", "Metronome"],
    answer: "Sheet music",
    category: "music",
  },
];
